business.qld.gov.au 2019-04-06

# Privacy | Business Queensland

The Queensland Government manages personal information in line with the [_Information Privacy Act 2009_](https://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/view/html/inforce/current/act-2009-014).

'Personal information' has a broad definition and may include, but is not limited to, your name, address, phone number or email address - basically any information that will identify you.

If you provide your personal information, we may collect and manage it in our Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system as described on this page, unless we tell you otherwise when we collect your personal information.

## Information we may request

We may ask you to provide information that includes personal information when we contact you, for example, if you:

  * request a service, submit an enquiry or seek feedback through the Business Queensland website
  * attend 1 of our events or meetings (e.g. we may ask you to leave a business card or sign an attendance register)
  * respond to 1 of our surveys
  * apply to participate in our grant or mentoring programs.

We will only request your personal information for the purposes of:

  * meeting your needs (e.g. providing a requested service or referring your request to the appropriate Queensland Government agency)
  * seeking to better understand customer needs (e.g. collecting feedback and information on issues impacting small business, and assessing the quality of our services to you)
  * to establish a register of our customers for the purpose of initiating future contact in relation to issues affecting small business and Queensland Government services.

Business Queensland delivers information and services on behalf of multiple Queensland Government departments. The number of services will grow as more agencies, including statutory authorities, migrate their business-facing services to Business Queensland.

The personal information you provide will be stored in our Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system. This information may be shared with authorised officers within other government agencies so they can respond to your specific request, or to engage with you as a small business operator to help improve the quality of government services provided to business and industry.

## Cookies

We use cookies to collect anonymous statistical information, including:

  * your browser, computer platform and screen resolution
  * your answers to optional questions in forms on our site
  * your traffic patterns through our site, such as: 
    * date and time of your visit
    * pages and documents accessed
    * subjects you searched for on our site
    * website you visited before ours
    * your ISP or server address.

Transactional services available from this site may use cookies to track business processes. Please read the particular service's privacy and security statement before beginning a transaction.

## 'Customise this site' form

  * Any responses provided on the Business Queensland ['Customise this site' form](https://www.business.qld.gov.au/discover) will be used to customise content to suit your needs. The objective is to ensure relevant content and services are prioritised when you visit our site.
  * Any page being customised will carry a clear indication of this, with options to turn off customisation. You can change how the content is being customised by returning to this form and making the desired changes.
  * We will not give the personal information you provide to other third parties without your consent, unless required by law.
  * We may collect anonymous data to discover and analyse trends in usage.

Please note that a planned update of this site will include capacity for automatic customisation of content for you, based on information about your use of the site. This information may be stored on secure external servers run by a third party bound by contractual obligation to comply with the _Information Privacy Act 2009_. This information may be linked to the information collected above to improve your experience on our site. You will be able to opt out of this process at any time.

## Use and disclosure of personal information

To meet your needs or answer your questions, we may share your personal information with other Queensland Government agencies who are also bound by the [_Information Privacy Act 2009_](https://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/view/html/inforce/current/act-2009-014). We will only disclose your personal information with those agencies in order to meet your requested service requirements.

Information stored in the CRM may also be used for service analysis and to communicate relevant and related government information and services to you (e.g. workshops, seminars, grant programs). You will be able to opt out of receiving these communications at any time.

The Queensland Government is committed to ensuring you are satisfied with the service we provide and may from time to time invite you to complete a survey about your satisfaction. Surveys may be conducted by contracted service providers who will be required to comply with the provisions of the _Information Privacy Act 2009_.

We will not add you to a mailing list, or give your personal information to third parties without your consent, except to provide you with services or improve our service to you, as indicated above, unless required by law.

## Applications for access to or amendment of personal information

To update your contact information, please contact the program area you have been engaging with directly, or enter your details and phone number in the 'Ask a question' feedback form in the footer below.

Formal requests for documents or amendment of personal information must be made by using a Right to Information application on the prescribed statutory forms. Copies of the forms are available from [www.rti.qld.gov.au](http://www.rti.qld.gov.au/). Before lodging an access or amendment application for information held by this department, please contact RTI Services for advice at [rtiservices@des.qld.gov.au](mailto:rtiservices@des.qld.gov.au).

## Emails

Our privacy principles apply to emails as well.

Our internet service provider or information technology staff may monitor email traffic for system troubleshooting and maintenance purposes only.

## Website analytics

We use Google Analytics on our website to gather anonymous information about visitors to our website. When you visit our web pages, your browser automatically sends anonymous information to Google. Some examples of the type of information includes, the web address of the page you're visiting, your IP address and demographic information. Google may also use cookies.

We use this data to analyse the pages that are visited to improve your experience and make sure our website is useful.

You can read more about [how Google uses data](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). You can choose not to allow Google to collect your information by [opting out of Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

## Security

Parts of this site transmit information securely across the internet, however, we recognise that there may be risks in doing so. Where we become aware of any security breach we will immediately move to correct the breach and endeavour to notify you as soon as possible.

Where this site contains links to other Queensland Government agencies' websites, the privacy or security terms set out there will apply to the material on those websites.

Where this site contains links to non-Queensland Government websites, the Queensland Government is not responsible for the privacy or security practices or the content of any such websites and we encourage you to review the privacy policies of those sites.

## How you can complain about our handling of your personal information

A privacy complaint is a complaint made by an individual about an act or practice of a department constituting a breach of our obligations under the _Information Privacy Act 2009_ in relation to that individual's personal information.

Privacy complaints should be made no longer than 12 months from the date when the act or practice the complaint is about occurred.

If you wish to lodge a privacy complaint, please:

  * submit your complaint in writing
  * include your address which we can use to contact you
  * and
  * include details about the actions or practice you are complaining about.

Mark your complaint as Private and Confidential, and address it to:

Complaints  
Legal Services  
Department of Employment, Small Business and Training  
PO Box 15483  
BRISBANE  QLD  4002

Email: [corporate.legal@desbt.qld.gov.au](mailto:corporate.legal@desbt.qld.gov.au)

The department will endeavour to respond to your concerns within 45 business days from the date your complaint is received.

However, in some circumstances, a longer period may be required in order to finalise your complaint. If so, you will be contacted with a view to arranging an extension of time.

On completion, you will be advised in writing of the department's decision, including any remedies that are considered appropriate to resolve the complaint.

## More information

If you would like to know more about information privacy, contact us by email on [corporate.legal@desbt.qld.gov.au](mailto:corporate.legal@desbt.qld.gov.au) or online by using the Office of the Information Commissioner's website [www.oic.qld.gov.au](https://www.oic.qld.gov.au/).
